Shengli Hu

CONTACT Information 546 Main St., A416 Phone: (213) 271-5530 New York, NY 10044 E-mail: sh2264@cornell.edu Cornell University Website: meredithhu.github.io

SELECTED
PUBLICATIONS
AND
CONFERENCES

Shengli Hu. "Somm, Into the Model". 2018. In Proceedings of *Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP 2018)*. [Question Answering, Siamese Neural Networks, Topic Models]

Shengli Hu, and Ali Borji. "Understanding Perceptual and Conceptual Fluency at a Large Scale". 2018. In Proceedings of *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV 2018)*. [Image Processing, Convolutional Neural Networks, Cognition & Perception, Information Theory]

Shawn Mankad, **Shengli Hu**, and Anandasivam Gopal. "Single Stage Prediction with Embedded Topic Modeling of Online Reviews for Mobile App Management". 2017. **Annals of Applied Statistics**. [Non-negative Matrix Factorization, Optimization]

Shengli Hu. "Understanding Visual and Conceptual Fluency at a Large Scale". 2017. International Conference of Computer Vision (ICCV 2017), Mutual Benefits of Cognitive and Computer Vision (MBC) Workshop. [Convolutional Neural Networks, Visualization]

Shengli Hu. "Never Tell Me the Odds: How Belief Dynamics Shape Audience Experience in Sports". Spotlight talk at the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2017) Workshop on Natural Language Processing and Computational Social Science (NLP+CSS). [Functional Data Analysis, Behavioral Economics, Vector Autoregression]

Shengli Hu. "Information Design and Audience Experience". 2017. *Marketing Science Conference*. [Word Embeddings, Support Vector Machines, Bayesian Updating, Behavioral Economics]

Shengli Hu. "Dynamics of Ideation in Crowdsourcing Platforms". 2013. The Institute for Operations Research and the Management Sciences (INFORMS) Annual Conference. [Game/Contract Theory, Signaling]

Shengli Hu, and Weixin Shang. 2012. "Managing Green Supply: Carbon Labeling Implications in Supply Chains". *INFORMS International Conference*. [Game/Contract Theory, Signaling]

SELECTED WORK
IN PROGRESS
AND UNDER
SUBMISSION

Shengli Hu. Detecting Concealed Information in Text and Speech [Language Models, Speech Processing, Computational Linguistics] Submitted to ACL 2019

Shengli Hu. Acoustic-Prosodic Indicators of Concealed Information in Text and Speech [Speech Processing]

Shengli Hu. Linguistic Indicators of Concealed Information in Text and Speech

Shengli Hu. A Trip Down Memory Lane: Identifying and 3D Reconstructing Memorable Experiences in the Wild [3D Reconstruction, Image Similarity, Parallel Search]

[Book] Somm: Into the Model — When Sommelier Meets Data Science

EDUCATION

Cornell University, Ithaca, New York

Ph.D., Information Management, Johnson School of Management, 2019

• Dissertation: "Information Design with Big Data"

M.S. Information Management, 2018

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California

Coursework in Economics and Operations, Dept of Economics, 2014

Fudan University, Shanghai, China

B.S., Management Science, School of Management¹, 2012

SOFTWARES, LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS

Fluent: Python (Tensorflow, keras, nltk, opency, etc.) & R, bash, LATEX, AWS EC2, SQL, English, Mandarin; Classroom Study: Julia, C/C++, Octave, Stata, Italian, German, Spanish, French, High Valyrian.

Professional EXPERIENCE

Citibank (Operations Intern) GE Capital (Marketing Intern) HSBC (New Product Development Intern)

Teaching EXPERIENCE Introduction to Programming in R and SQL (TA; Spring 2016, 2017); Advanced Data Analytics Applications and Methods (TA: Spring 2016, 2017); International Marketing (TA: Spring 2016)

SCHOLARSHIPS

Renmin Scholarship, 2009-2012; Honor Thesis, Fudan University, 2012

Sage Fellowship, Cornell University, 2014-2018

Conference Grants, Graduate School, 2015-2018; Travel Award, EMNLP, 2018

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE AND SERVICE

Researcher at the Lab for Experimental Economics & Decision Research (LEEDR), 2015

• Sourcing Network Formation via Stable Matching: Theory and Experiments

Research Assistant at the Los Angeles Behavioral Economics Laboratory (LABEL), 2014

• Time preference and preference of time; Shaming strategies to deter online piracy; Neuroeconomic foundations of Weak Axiom of Revealed Preferences

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{PHD}}$ Coursework Advanced Artificial Intelligence Advanced Computer Vision Networks, Crowds and Markets (Audit) Advanced Machine Learning

> Advanced Topics in Econometrics II Empirical Strategies for Policy Analysis II

NLP and Social Interaction Functional Data Analysis

Economics and Politics Econometrics for Network Analysis Dynamic Optimization Bayesian Statistics in Marketing Seminar in Cognitive Science Seminar in Computer Graphics Seminar in Artificial Intelligence Quant Marketing Seminar

Empirical Industrial Organization (Audit) Computationally Intensive Methods

Theory of Linear Models Text Mining History and Literature (Audit) Optimization Over Time Semi/Non-parametric Econometrics (Audit) Experimental Economics Marketing Strategy and Mix Models Econometric Methods Probability and Statistics for Economists

Microeconomic Theory I: Consumer Theory Microeconomic Theory II: Contract Theory Practice of Econometrics Current Research in OM I: Stochastic Models

Current Research in OM II: Revenue Management Elements of Stochastic Processes

Inventory and Supply Chain Theory Cognition and Learning (Audit)

¹The highest ranked business school in mainland China based on research as of 2018